Let's learn about three traversal in sea traversing a tree means visiting every node in the tree.
You might, for instance, want to add all the values in the tree or find the largest one for all of
these operations.
You might need to visit each node of the tree.
Linear data structures like erase their excuse and linkages have only one way to read the data.
But the hierarchical data structure, like a tree, can be traversed in different way.
And we have learned about the in order traversal, the pre-order traversal and the post order traversal.
Let's implement them into into language.
See, and then in the next video, we will solve the exercise that learn us the truth reversal in Java.
So.
We start by including this studio, and this did the Idlib study live.
That edge and we create this structured note.
So this is the basic of this node and we have and learn about the node and we learn about that.
It has a left and right.
So there is no point.
Turn the left and the right that do linkage and we have the entire term because we are going to create
a tree of integers.
OK?
You can substitute or replace the end with any type of data that you want, but we prefer using the
end in this course in order to make everything simple and easy to understand.
OK.
So this struck note contains the data I called item and we have a note to the left, and we thought
it would have a note to the right or to the left or the right.
Let's see how to make in order traversal in order traversal.
Please go back to the previous videos in order to.
I learned about the in order traversal, which is left, root and right.
So the first step in order traversal will make visit all the nodes in the left step three, then the
root node, then visit all the nodes in the right.
Sub three OK, left.
Root right.
It took the road as tracked north, which is the route.
What is the route of this tree?
We specify it and a fruit equal equal to no, then return.
And we make in order traversal.
This is that occurred and we call in order traversal and we get through to that left a fruit equal,
equal to null, then return.
So we go to the we go to the in order traversal a recursion operation by specifying and passing route
to the left.
So we are going to the left.
And if there is a left, so go again and again and again until we have a stopping condition, a fruit
equal equal to none.
Then we need to return by returning, we can go back in the recursion.
Please go back to the recursion section in order to learn more about that mechanism behind the recursion.
Now printing the root, we print the route item.
And now when we finished the left, we go in order traversal and we passed the route to the right.
So every time we go and make in order Traverso pass through to the right through to the right until
reaching a root equal to none.
OK, so this is this method contained double recursion in order traversal when we pass through to the
left and in order traversal when we go to the right, you see guys how we can specify and we go deeply
into that at three until reaching a nun.
So we go to the left route to the left.
We print the route route item and then we go to the right.
This is the old order outshoot we have in order traversal.
This is the left that we will print the left.
This is will print the route item.
We get the route and now we are going to print in order traversal to the right.
So we start from the left.
We go to the top to the route and we go printing to the right.
OK, now.
Let's continue with.
Pre-order traversal, pre-order traversal, this traversal tells us to visit the root node.
Visit all the notes that left Sept. three and visit all the nodes in that tree.
OK, so root left and right.
We start by checking if root equal equal to null, then return.
So we have we have reached a node that does not have any siblings.
Brent fruit.
All right.
We print that a fruit first step, second step, we go and and call again the method, pre-order traversal
and route to that left.
So we are going to print all all the pre-order traversal to the left and we start executing that pre-order
traversal.
But here we pass through to the right.
So the first step we've put in the route, the second step, we print the left section and we start
by right up to the last step.
This is the pre-order Traverse the post order.
Traverso tells us to visit all the nodes in the sub three in the left sub three.
The second step is visit all the notes to the right step three and the last step is visit the root note.
So we start by checking if root equal equal to null, then return post order traversal method.
As a new recursion, we pass through to the left post order traversal route.
So the post over there traversal to the left and post order traversal to the right, and then we'll
print the route right this post over the traverse, OK?
And we have talked about them in the previous videos.
Now let's create the node struct node, create the known, and this method will create a new node by
reserving a memory.
My local memory allocation and we start Nuno's new node data equal to the value that it is best.
The new node left equal to null.
And then you know that I'm equal to none.
So we specify that the pointer to the left and the right, they are none.
Let's create a method that insert on the left of the note, so we specify the route and we specify an
end value as padding meter to the insert left method, and we start by creating the route to the left
equal to create note.
So we called that previously created Create A. Method, and we passed the value because we are specifying
it to the left and the route return route to the left and now insert the right to the right of the note.
We get the struct node, root and value.
We put a root right equal to create node.
So we specify the creation of the node and return route to the right.
OK.
The main let's test them and our program struck note we create the route, insert left and we specify
the route that there's a road and 12 insert to the right, nine insert left.
A route left whispered, hate you, sure, you see guys that we specify that route left five and a route
left five six and we print in order traversal in order to traverse on the route.
He ordered traversal to the route and post order traversal.
I want from you to put these methods and write a program in C and put this data into the compiler and
start testing and playing with the three traversal OK in order to understand very well how this mechanics
work.
I want also from you to write them down because they are very important and I, I I am waiting your
solution.
I want from you to post the solution of all of this video after making these in the main and I am waiting
any questions, any answer, any answers for this problem.
Unlike in order traversal, pre-order traversal and post order traversal our how we can write a better
code.
Also, I want from you if you have any doubts, any suggestions, any recommendation for this course,
I want from you to comment below.
So let's go now to see how to make three traversal in Java by creating a program that we have.